闪 电 侠
第六季
第十一集
惊喜  亲爱的
Surprise, babe.
确实惊喜
Yeah, wow.
这次不是香蕉
This is not a banana.
我知道还有几天才到情人节
I know Valentine's Day isn't for a couple of days,
不过我想何不提前
but I thought why not?
我要在这周的
Let me surprise my hubby
疯狂超能力者袭击前  给老公一个惊喜
before some crazy meta-of-the-week strikes.
等等  我来
Here, wait, I got it.
你的胳膊还好吗
How's your arm?
还是刺痛  但已经好些了
I mean, it stings, but it's a bit better.
是吗
Yeah?
如果你真的想吃香蕉
You know, if you really want a banana,
我可以去厨房...
I could always go in the kitchen...
不不  我不需要香蕉
No, no. No, I don't need a banana.
这看起来棒极了
This all looks awesome.
这些松饼非常的...
I mean, the pancakes are really...
圆
round.
迫不及待想尝尝它们
Excited to taste 'em
用我的嘴尝
with my mouth.
我的天
Oh, my God.
你什么时候学会...
When did you learn to...
我是说这太好吃了
I mean, these are really good.
-谢谢  -真的好吃
- Thank you. - Yeah.
这是鲜榨果汁吗
Is this fresh-squeezed?
我们如今可能拥有了一台非常贵的榨汁机
We may or may not now own a very expensive juicer.
不得不说你这一早给了我足够的惊喜
Gotta say, you're full of surprises this morning.
今天才刚刚开始呢
Well, the day is young.
你怎么有时间
Wait, how did you have time
做这么多东西
to get a spread like this together?
貌似昨天挺疯狂的
I mean, it sounded like yesterday was insane.
确实是
Yeah, it was,
所以公民报小队在继续调查卡夫之前
which is why Team Citizen is regrouping
要重组一下
before we go after Carver again.
至于这些
And as for all this,
要感谢有24小时杂货铺
thank God for 24-hour grocery stores.
阿门
Amen.
为您提醒
This is your reminder.
您预订了2月14号晚上7点钟
You have a reservation at Giovanni's
在乔瓦尼餐厅的晚餐
February 14th at 7:00 p.M.
你猜怎么着
You know what?
如果我们今晚也预订一个晚餐
If we also made a reservation for tonight,
我们来一个没有紧急情况的
we could up our chances
情人节晚餐的可能性就会大一些
of having an emergency-free Valentine's Day dinner.
只要我们一起过情人节
Well, I don't care when we have dinner,
我不在乎什么时候吃饭
as long as we're together.
Alexa  中午提醒我
Alexa, set a reminder
亚马逊语音助手
给乔瓦尼餐厅打电话
to call Giovanni's today at noon.
好的  到时我会提醒您
Okay, I'll remind you.
真棒  你把早饭吃完
Great. You finish eating.
-肯定吃完  -我去洗个澡
- I will. - I'm gonna go take a shower.
好的
Okay.
你棒呆了
You're amazing.
你个小混球
Son of a motherless goat.
别想挑战我的耐心
You do not want to test me.
谢天谢地  还好只是你
Ah, thank God it's just you.
你没胶带了
You're out of tape.
你自己进来的吗
Did you just let yourself in?
放松
Relax.
我又不是个擅长瞄准
I'm not some whack job meta-killer
或有不可告人的动机的疯狂超能力杀手
with crazy good aim and ulterior motives.
不再是了
Anymore.
光博士再上门拜访一次确实会很糟
Another house call from Dr. Light would suck,
但我说的是纳什
but I was actually talking about Nash.
他现在简直是一级跟屁虫
He's a total stage-one clinger.
你昨天不是中枪了吗
Didn't you get shot yesterday?
你不应该在一个放满
Shouldn't you be soaking
冷冻青豆的浴缸里泡着什么的吗
in a tub of frozen peas or something?
然后错过我的第一次情人节吗
And miss out on my first Valentine's Day?
当然不行
No way!
我讨厌情人节
I hate Valentine's Day,
而且我还有很多工作要做  所以
and I have a lot of work to do, so...
知道吗  据我所知
You know, it's my understanding
讨厌情人节的人有两种
that there are two kinds of people who hate Valentine's Day.
第一种认为这是巨石糖果公司捏造出来的节日
One, those who think it's a made-up holiday by Big Candy,
或是第二种  心碎的人
or two, those with a broken heart.
我认为你是第二种
I think you're the second one.
我不是
No. I'm not.
是吗  其实我觉得你是
Really? I think actually you are.
我认为这个玩情绪摇滚的
And I think Mr. Emerson Fairweather
爱默生·费尔韦瑟
又一个等待爱情的情人节
爱默生·费尔韦瑟先生是始作俑者
is the emo dope who's responsible.
我们是在他的乐队演出后认识的
We met after a gig his band played.
总之  我们没成
Anyway, it didn't work out.
又一个等待爱情的情人节
开始喝酒吧
喝咖啡不喝鸡尾酒
又一个等待爱情的情人节
"Another Valentine's Day waiting for love.
开始喝酒吧
Let the drinking begin.
标签是  喝咖啡不喝鸡尾酒
#CoffeeNotCocktails."
你们俩天生一对
Look, you're perfect for each other.
你们有共同点
You have something in common.
你们俩都那么悲惨
You're both miserable.
谢谢你提醒我
Thanks for the reminder.
也许你和翻闹小子先生
You know, maybe you and Mr. Fall Out Boy
可以一起玩  一起闷闷不乐
can go off and be mopey together,
然后你就不会讨厌情人节了
and then you wouldn't hate Valentine's Day.
抱歉  我认识你吗
I'm sorry, have we met?
这上面说
Look, says here
他明天会回吉特斯咖啡
he's gonna be back at Jitters tomorrow.
喜欢新吉特斯咖啡的装潢
明天也许会去
你猜怎么着  我们也去
And you know what? So are we.
因为我要让你们俩复合
'Cause I'm gonna get the two of you back together
找回情人节爱情
for some V-Day love.
丘比特要求的
Cupid demands it.
什么
What?
我很高兴我们决定今晚一起共进晚餐
I'm glad we decided to do dinner tonight.
虽然还没到日子  但是一起庆祝情人节
It's awesome celebrating Valentine's together,
实在太棒了
even if it's early.
是啊
Yeah.
没有危机和暗淡的未来向我们袭来
No Crisis, no dark future looming over us.
感觉很好
Feels nice.
真的很好
It really does.
晚上好
Buonasera.
很对不起  我们不会说意大利语
I'm so sorry. We don't speak Italian.
可以给我们点时间吗
And can we just get another minute?
谢谢
Grazie.
怎么
What?
你会说意大利语吗
What-- do you speak Italian?
这个嘛
Oh, well--
你知道几个月前
you know that story that I was writing
我写的那篇关于小意大利的报道吗
a few months ago on Little Italy?
我学会了一两句
Well, I picked up a phrase or two.
比如说该死
Like porca miseria.
那是个骂人的词
It's a curse word,
但字面上是"痛苦至极"的意思
but it literally means "Pig misery."
很奇怪吧
Yeah, weird, right?
玫瑰是红色的
Roses are red,
紫罗兰是蓝色的
violets are blue,
站出来  索尔•弗兰克尔
step forward, Saul Frankel,
不然我就杀光你们所有人
or I'll kill all of you.
人们说骑士精神已死
And they say chivalry is dead.
把箱子交出来 亲爱的
Hand over the case, Love.
你知道如果你把它拿走会怎么样
You know what will happen if you take this.
我知道如果我不拿走
I know what will happen to you
你会怎么样
if I don't.
亲爱的两位
Darlings!
很久不见
Long time no see.
我打扰了你们的约会之夜吗
Did I interrupt date night?
中城警局
CCPD.
阿姆内特·布莱克
Amunet Black,
现在我要以抢劫和严重伤害罪逮捕你
I'm placing you under arrest for robbery and aggravated assault.
非常正式啊  艾伦先生
So very official, Mr. Allen.
你不就只是个犯罪现场调查员吗
But aren't you just a CSI?
我依然是警察  能逮捕你
I'm still a cop who can arrest you.
好吧
Oh, okay.
那请便吧
Well, by all means,
让我帮你开个头
let me help you with the first bit.
我有权利保持沉默
I have the right to remain silent,
这一点可非常实用
which will come in handy
如果你不想让那秘密身份小猫咪
if you don't want me letting that little secret identity cat
跳出那红闪闪小包的话
out of its flashy red bag.
所以我们为什么不把这个当做一次警告
So why don't we just call this a warning.
我这就离开  毫无损失
I'll be on my way. No harm.
毫无麻烦
No cowl.
我能就这么放你走吗
I'm supposed to just let you leave?
那当然了
Bloody right.
别想着来追我
Don't think of coming after me,
因为如果我看到了你
'cause if I see you,
或是你的连体衣
or your onesie,
或是任何你冷淡与柔韧的
or any one of your frigid or bendy
超级英雄朋友
superhero friends,
我会让你对此负责
I will hold it against all of you
告诉全世界你的真实身份
and tell the world your real identities.
了解
Savvy?
没错
That's right.
因为在所有伟大的男人身后都有一个女人
Because behind every great man is a woman
翻着白眼
rolling her eyes.
拜拜  亲爱的
Ta-ta, sweethearts!
约会夜就这么泡汤了
So much for date night.
苦恼至极
Pig misery.
没有阿姆内特的踪迹吗
There's no trace of Amunet?
就好像她消失了一样
It's like she vanished.
是啊  她有时会这样
Yeah, she does that.
有任何传闻说她回城里了吗
Were there any rumblings that she was back in town?
没有  但是韦斯特队长让所有警官
None, but Captain West has all officers searching
在高度警惕下搜寻
on high alert.
好吧  谢了  科博尔
All right, thanks, Korber.
巴里  阿姆内特隐蔽了那么久
Barry, Amunet has been off the grid for so long
如果她现在回来
that if she's back,
一定是有什么大的坏事要发生
it must be for something big and bad,
而我很肯定那和她偷走的设备有关
and I'm pretty sure it involves that device that she stole.
我知道
I know.
别担心  我们会找到她的
Hey, don't worry. We're gonna find her.
我只是  我不敢相信我站在那里
I just--I can't believe I just stood there
就那么让她走了
and let her walk out.
巴里  那不是你的错
Barry, it's not your fault.
我们知道她知道你身份这事
We knew that her knowing your identity
会回来反咬一口
would come back to bite us.
好吧  是时候用老办法
All right, well, time to fight her
来打败她了
the old-fashioned way.
我去搜寻一下整座城市
I'm gonna run some sweeps of the city.
等等  她说了不能穿连体衣
Whoa, whoa, she said no onesies.
求你别学着那么叫
Please don't call it that.
我想说的是  我们不能冒风险
What I'm trying to say is we can't risk her
让她暴露闪电小队
putting Team Flash on blast.
好  但我们也不能什么都不做
Okay, but we also can't do nothing.
我们不会
Well, we won't.
如果你想找出一个犯罪者的计划
If you want to figure out a criminal's plan,
就去拜访他们的操场
visit their playground.
这是个坏主意
This is a bad idea.
挑战整个贩毒集团进行小刀对决
Challenging an entire drug cartel to a knife fight,
那才是坏主意
that's a bad idea.
倒是很有趣
Fun, though.
这个  这不算什么
This, this is nothing.
过去和他聊聊就是了
Just go over there and talk to him.
他看起来确实挺悲惨的
He really does look miserable.
我敢肯定他在写些伤感的垃圾歌
I'm sure he's over there working on some sad sack song
为了明晚的表演用
to perform tomorrow night.
相信你的人生导师  直接过去就是了
Trust your awesome life coach, and just get over there.
-那我说些什么  -我不知道
- Well, what do I even say? - I don't know.
你说你在他身边可以做自己
You said you could be yourself around him,
所以就去这么做
so go do that.
你说得对
You're right.
别担心
Don't worry.
我确定他们只是好朋友关系
I'm sure they're just good friends.
两个特别好的朋友
A really good friend.
-阿莱格拉  -我就知道这是个坏主意
- Allegra - I knew this was a bad idea.
你下次想当人生导师的话  还是算了
Next time you want to play life coach, don't.
尖端科研实验室
我还是觉得应该我去
I still think it's better if I go.
宝贝  所有人都知道这
Babe, this is a known spot
是阿姆内特用来招募的地方
that Amunet used to recruit her crew.
再说了  一个警察怎么可能大摇大摆地走进去
Besides, a cop can't just waltz in there.
好吧  但是这里大部分都是罪犯
Okay, but it's mostly criminals in there.
真的很危险
It's really dangerous.
巴里  我的工作就是从别人那里获取信息
Barry, it's my job to get information out of people.
阿姆内特肯定不在那里
Amunet's not gonna be there,
但是如果有人知道她要去干什么
but if someone knows where she's headed next,
我可以让他们告诉我  这就是我的工作
I can get them to talk. It's what I do.
再不济  如果事情变严峻  我们不还有暗号
Besides, if things get dicey, we have our code word.
香蕉
Banana.
你听到我说这个了  你就飞速溜走
You hear that, you come fathwooming.
好吧  当心点  拜托了
Okay, fine. Just be safe, please.
以童子军的荣耀发誓
Scout's honor.
威士忌  加冰
Whiskey, rocks.
你看起来很眼熟
You look familiar.
他肯定读《中城市民》  快出来
He must read the "Citizen." Get out.
出来  从那里出来  爱瑞丝
Get out. Get out of there, Iris.
可能我长着张大众脸吧
Maybe I have one of those faces.
我在找阿姆内特·布莱克
I'm looking for Amunet Black.
你看起来不是她喜欢的类型
You don't seem like her type.
有什么问题吗  拉尔斯
Got a problem, Lars?
香蕉
Banana.
香蕉  香蕉
Banana. Banana!
香蕉
Banana.
香蕉  香蕉
Banana, banana.
香蕉  爱瑞丝
Banana, Iris!
我现在看起来像吗
Now do I seem like her type?
看起来我需要一个新保安了
Seems like I need a new bouncer.
有兴趣吗
You interested?
我有兴趣再找你
I'll keep it in mind.
我问最后一遍  阿姆内特在哪
Now for the last time, where is Amunet?
我听说
Last I heard,
她要劫走一项专业技术
she was heisting some specialized tech
从这里
from this spot.
谢谢你的酒
Thanks for the drink.
发生什么了  我听到玻璃碎的声音了
Hey, what happened? I heard glass breaking.
没什么  我把一个酒瓶砸一废物的头上了
Nothing. I broke a bottle over some loser's head.
-什么  -巴里  不用担心
- You what? - Barry, don't worry.
什么事都没有
Everything's fine.
我就是为了获取信息演了一下
I was playing a role to get information.
好吧  那你也有点过火了
Okay, well, that was maybe crossing a line.
我相信他们有自己的黑道医生
I'm sure they have some sort of mob doctor
在里面
in there somewhere.
好吧  但  我的意思是这么做很鲁莽
Okay, but, I mean, it was reckless,
而且还可能适得其反
and it could've backfired.
但是什么事都没有  因为我知道我在干什么
But it didn't, because I knew what I was doing.
而且我得到这个了
And we got this.
伊沃实验室
这就是阿姆内特的下一个目标吗
Is this Amunet's next target?
我们一起去抓她吧
Let's go get her.
我是真的喜欢爆炸声
Ooh, I do love loud noises.
太棒了
Yeah.
送给拥有一切的我
For the lady who has everything.
看起来你在酒吧得到的消息是对的
Well, your source at the bar was right.
她来了
She's here.
是啊  但是她在干什么
Yeah, but what is she doing?
你知道那是什么东西吗
Any idea what that tech is?
不知道
No.
但是我敢说这跟她偷的第一个设备有关
But I'm betting it's connected to the first device she stole.
我们应该研究一下怎么阻止她
We have to figure out how to stop her,
在一切变得更糟
before things get--
之前
Worse.
这正是我在找的
Just what I was looking for.
金面人跟阿姆内特是一伙的
Goldface is working with Amunet?
他们过去确实有一腿
Well, they did used to date.
你来得太晚了  基斯
You're too late, Keith.
莱斯莉
Oh, Leslie.
你知道我不能让你带它走
You know I can't let you leave with that.
我觉得他们没有合作
I don't think they're working together.
是的
No.
这是场群架
This is a gang war.
我想你到这里来
I suppose you're here
是要偷我的东西
to steal what's mine.
一贯如此
Typical.
什么是你的
What's yours?
亲爱的  那个设备是我的
Baby, that device belongs to me.
又来了
Oh, here we go again
还是这么有占有欲
with the possessive man routine.
那些黑胶唱片是我的  基斯
The vinyl records were mine, Keith.
你什么时候喜欢电台司令乐队
Since when did you like Radiohead?
我有《OK电脑》的180克黑胶唱片
I had "OK Computer" on 180 gram vinyl
而且是三折叠唱片封套
with a triple gatefold sleeve!
夸张了
Overrated.
你溜走时带走了
You skipped out
我的《冲出康普顿》原声带
with my "Straight Outta Compton" soundtrack!
得了吧  好像你遇到我之前
Oh, please, like you even knew who N.W.A were
认得异见人士乐队一样
before you met me!
安保  不许动
Security, freeze!
都不许动
Don't anybody move.
那个需要时间来解决
Took some doing setting up that deal,
你居然带着我的音乐从乔瓦尼餐厅溜走
and you just stroll out of Giovanni's with my score?
抱歉没感到抱歉
Sorry not sorry.
-宝贝  -我说了不许动
- Baby. - I said freeze!
你知道我不会让事情变成这样的
You know I'm not letting it go down like that.
不是吧
Oh, come on.
看来某人失手了
Looks like somebody's lost their touch.
我说了把手举起来
I said put your hands in the air!
真的吗
Really?
我倒觉得某人不再去健身房了
Looks to me like somebody's lost their gym membership.
警告  电气危险源
-巴里  -怎么了
- Barry. - What?
如果阿姆内特知道闪电侠在这就糟了
It'll be bad if Amunet knows the Flash is here.
是的  但那个保安可能会受重伤
Yeah, but that guard might get really hurt.
我得做些什么
I have to do something.
伊沃实验室
设备精良  禁止靠近
泡再多的健身房
Yeah, well, no amount of gym time
我也不能拎起来你的行李
could help me lift all your baggage!
还是能拎起来这家伙的
Still strong enough to lift this though.
你还好吗  没事吧
You okay? You okay?
再见  费利西娅
Bye, Felicia.
你怎么提起来的
How did you lift that?
肾上腺素
Uh...adrenaline.
呆在这别动  你会没事的
Stay here, okay? You'll be okay.
或许吧
Probably.
他们在哪
Where are they?
-走了  -什么
- Gone. - What?
咱们去追他们吧  我们必须拿到那个箱子
Well, let's go after them. We have to get the case.
谁还需要箱子
Who needs the case
当你已经拿到里面的东西
when you've got what's inside?
我的天
Ah. Oh, my God.
你找到什么了吗
Hey. Did you find anything?
你为什么这么疲惫
Why are you so tired?
我不知道
I don't know, I mean--
为了不让阿姆内特和金面人看到我
I mean, to keep Amunet and Goldface from seeing me,
我不得不跑快  快到几乎是隐形的
I had to run so fast I was practically invisible,
但越来越糟了
but it's getting bad out there.
他们那些帮派开始交易袭击了
I mean, their gangs are just trading attacks.
好像两边都认为
It's like both sides think
另一边有第二个设备
that the other has the second device.
我给我爸打电话了
Yeah. I called my dad.
他说阿姆内特和金面人
He said that Amunet and Goldface
紧跟犯罪对象
are sticking to criminal targets
比如对方的藏匿屋  但
like each other's stash houses, but...
我不知道  我觉得
I don't know, I think
他们想伤害对方
they're trying to hurt each other,
不仅仅是他们的生意
not just their businesses.
好吧
Okay. All right.
在查明他们的目的之前
Well, until we know what they're after,
我还是继续用超级速度巡逻吧
I guess I'll just keep patrolling at super speed.
我只是担心会有无辜的人
I'm just worried some innocent people
在我们等待这件事平息时
are gonna get caught in their crossfire
会被卷入他们的交火
while we wait for this thing to blow over.
我觉得这件事不会平息下来  巴里
I don't think it will, Barry.
阿姆内特和金面人在伊沃实验室发生争执时
When Amunet and Goldface were arguing at Ivo,
用的是对方的真名
they used each other's real names.
他们在争论老唱片收藏
They argued about an old record collection.
这是很私人的事
That's personal.
私人恩怨不会轻易平息
Personal doesn't just blow over.
但是盗窃技术装置怎么会是私人恩怨
But what's personal about stealing tech?
我给蔡瑞安打了电话
Okay, so I called Ryan Choi.
阿姆内特偷的第一件装置
The first item that Amunet stole?
是一台特制的紫外线投影仪
A specialized UV projector.
第二件装置是生物群落模拟仓库
The second item was a biome simulated storage unit.
把它们组合在一起
If you combine the two,
可以用来运输脆弱的植物性生物
it can be used to transport delicate, plant-based life.
他们在找一种植物  为什么
They're after a plant? Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
但如果他们在找的话  它可能很危险
But if those two are after it, it's probably dangerous.
没错
Yeah.
我之前写报道时认识的一个植物学家
So a botanist source I used from an old story
正在调查这件事
is looking into it,
但是有一个更直接的解决方法
but I think there's a faster way to figure this out.
我们把阿姆内特想要的给她
We give Amunet what she wants.
-什么  -没错
- What? - Yeah.
我们利用现有的筹码  接近阿姆内特
We use the leverage we have, we get close to Amunet,
从内部解决这件事
and we solve this thing from the inside.
不行
No.
这样做太过危险了
I mean, that's way too dangerous.
-阿姆内特认识我们俩  -那又怎样
- I mean, Amunet knows both of us. - So?
我们要按兵不动
So we stay put.
你的意思是要我不动
You mean I stay put
而你去巡逻
while you patrol.
我是说
Well, I mean--
你是闪电侠  你最懂  对吗
You're the Flash. You know best, right?
什么  爱瑞丝  拜托
What? Iris, come on.
我们得看清事实
I mean, look at the facts--
去他的事实  巴里
Screw facts, Barry.
我相信我的直觉
I trust my intuition.
是直觉让我从暗杀中活了下来
My intuition, by the way, that saved my life from an assassin
而那时你正在某座岛上
while you were on some island.
什么
What?
等等  到底怎么了
What's-- okay, what's going on?
自从那天晚上你回到家之后
It feels like ever since you came back home the other night,
就变得和以前不一样了
you've been acting kind of different.
薄煎饼  还有砸碎的瓶子
I mean, the pancakes and the bottle smashing--
你知道自己在说什么吗  巴里
Do you hear yourself right now, Barry?
你是认真的吗
Seriously?
我的新年愿望  学做薄煎饼
My New Year's resolution? Learn how to make pancakes.
而且我告诉过你  我是演的那出
And I told you that I was playing a role.
拜托  巴里
Come on, Barry.
你知道吗
You know what?
事实上
Actually,
我昨晚并没有把文件落在办公室
I didn't forget my files at the office last night.
我是去跟进一条线索  就这样
I was following up on a lead, so there.
你半夜去跟进一条线索
You were following a lead in the middle of the night?
你可能会遇到危险
I mean, something could have happened to you.
就是这样  巴里  问题就在这里
That, Barry. That right there.
这就是我为什么没告诉你  我不需要你救我
That's why I didn't tell you. I don't need you to save me.
我可以照顾好自己
I can handle myself.
我还有自己的小队  公民报小队
I even have my own team now, Team Citizen.
-我知道  -你知道吗
- I know. - And you know what?
你在全身心对抗危机的时候
While you were preoccupied with Crisis,
我在学着适应没有你的生活
I was planning to start a life without you,
这是我做过最难的事
and it was the hardest thing that I ever had to do,
但我还是做了  因为是你请求的  巴里
but I did it because you asked me to, Barry.
我愿意为你做任何事  你知道这点
I would do anything for you, and you know that,
但我不能再做等你拯救的落难少女了
but I can't be your damsel in distress anymore,
而且我也不能再做你面罩里的声音
and I cannot be the voice inside your cowl
为你鼓劲
cheering you on.
我是个记者  巴里  而且非常优秀
I'm a reporter, Barry, and I'm a damn good one,
不管有没有风险  我都应该跟你一样
and risky or not, I deserve to be in that field
出现在现场
just as much as you do.
我知道
I know that.
只是觉得好像...
It just feels like--
感觉好像我们已经很久没联系过了
I mean--it doesn't feel like we're connecting lately.
我成长了  巴里
I've grown, Barry.
而且我真的很为现在的自己骄傲
And I'm really proud of the person that I am today.
我只希望你也有同感
I just wish that you felt the same way too.
拜托  爱瑞丝
Come on, I-- Iris.
只有你一个人
It's just you.
对  我觉得可能是...
Yeah, I thought, you know, maybe it might be the--
你知道  那个女孩
you know, the girl, the--
她叫什么来着
what's her name?
阿波丹莎
Abbondanza.
阿莱格拉吗
Allegra?
对  阿莱格拉  就是她
Yeah, Allegra. That's her.
你为什么要找她
Why are you looking for her?
她是  这个
She's--she's--this--
纳米级别的短管螺旋钻具  是她的
nano-dimensional bucket auger, it's hers,
而且她想...  我以前用过短管螺旋钻
and she wanted-- I was bucket augering,
但现在她想用短管螺旋钻钻孔
but now she wants to bucket auger,
所以就像...  不管怎么说  你在干什么
so I was like-- anyway, what are you doing?
坐在这自斟自饮吗
Sitting here drinking by yourself?
对  在情人节这天喝酒
Yes, Valentine's Day drinking
庆祝我活得有多失败
to celebrate what a screw-up I am.
那是什么
What is that?
纳尔托人的蜂蜜酒
Naltorian mead,
以前的某位威尔斯留给我们的
left to us by one of the previous Wells.
你知道  以前多元宇宙里还有其他威尔斯
You know, back when there were other Wells in the multiverse.
对不起
Sorry.
纳什  我不是...
Nash, I didn't--
没事  没事
It's fine. It's fine.
你懂我的意思吗
See what I mean?
我碰过的所有东西都没有好结果
Everything I touch turns out sucking.
我该怎么跟拉尔夫解释
I mean, how do I explain to Ralph
他浪费了最后的五个月时间
that he's wasted the last five months
想要教我如何成为更好的人
trying to teach me how to be a better person?
因为不管我捡了多少垃圾
'Cause doesn't matter how much litter I pick up,
给多少生病的孩子念过书
how many sick kids I read to,
我还是无法理解别人
I still don't get people.
我真的觉得我可以帮阿莱格拉
I really thought I could help Allegra
跟前男友重修旧好
fall back in love with her ex,
但相反  我只是把一切都搞砸了
but instead, I just made a mess of everything.
你知道吗  你迷路了
You know, you got lost.
现在你只要重新回到大路上
Now you just get back on the highway,
找到跟阿莱格拉沟通的新方法
and find new inroads with this Allegra.
小菜一碟
Easy-peasy.
我不是很了解她
You know, I don't know her very well,
但也许她只是
but perhaps she's one of those people
看事情太绝对  对吗
that just sees things in absolutes, right?
非黑即白
Black and white.
任务只能失败或成功  对吗
Missions fail or succeed. Right?
你知道你要做什么吗
You know what you need to do?
你应该回到她身边
You need to get back in there with her.
开导她  告诉她
Open her up and show her
事情不是只有黑白两面  知道吗
that things aren't just black and white, you know?
非黑即白  只适用于...
Black and white, that's just for...
死亡和纳税
death and taxes.
其他的一切
Everything else,
其他的一切都是处于灰色之中
everything else happens in the grays.
看来某人不喜欢他
Someone's not a fan.
闪电侠太太
Mrs. Flash?
你怎么找到这里的
However did you find your way here?
好吧  有位特别有魅力的酒保
Well, there is a very charming bartender
在提供消息
that is giving out tips
而不是收取小费  所以...
rather than collecting them, so--
拉尔斯
Lars.
我得杀了他
I'll have to kill him.
女士优先
Ladies first.
等等
Ah, wait.
我知道你想做什么
I know what you're after.
我想加入
And I want in.
让我说明白
So let me get this straight.
爱瑞丝·韦斯特艾伦
Iris West-Allen,
一颗冉冉升起的新闻媒体新星
a skyrocketing news media force,
警局队长的女儿
daughter of the police captain,
红衣极速者钟情的配偶
devoted spouse of the Scarlet Speedster,
你这身份
all of that,
还要我相信你愿意
and I'm supposed to believe you're willing
把珍贵的被盗技术给我
to give me an invaluable piece of stolen tech?
为什么  说明白
Why, exactly?
伯西尼之女
Rappaccini's Daughter.
一种最近被运送到中城植物园的
A rare orchid recently shipped for study
稀有兰花
at CC Arboretum.
你又为何会认为
And why on this great big blue marble
我会对这有兴趣呢
do you think that I would be interested in that?
因为  它之所以稀有
Well, because what makes it rare
不是因为它25年一开花
isn't that it blooms every 25 years.
而是花的花粉
It's the flower's pollen.
当被适当加热后  它可以合成
When adequately heated, it can be synthesized
一种心灵感应麻醉剂
into a telepathic narcotic.
如果你能读心
If you can read minds,
那就很容易弄到那些富得流油的
it would be much easier to gain access to PIN numbers
银行账户密码了
to big, fat bank accounts.
好极了
Bravo!
干得漂亮
Well done!
但是你并没回答那个最重要的问题
But you didn't answer the most important question.
我到底为什么要相信你
Why the bloody hell should I believe you?
因为我想使用花粉
Because I want to use the pollen.
去干什么
For what?
正如你所知  我嫁给了闪电侠
Well, as you know, I am married to the Flash,
他是一个有很多心思的男人
and he's a man who has a lot on his mind.
而最近  并没花在我身上
And lately, that hasn't been me.
跟你实话实说
And to tell you the truth,
恐怕这些超级英雄的事
I'm afraid that all this superhero-ing
正在破坏我们的婚姻
is ruining my marriage.
但是如果我能使用花粉
But if I could use the pollen,
那我就能读懂他的心
then I could read his mind.
你为什么不早说
Oh, why didn't you just say so?
这我能相信
That I can believe!
姐妹  我对恋爱中的
Girl, I am no stranger
无赖手段可并不陌生
to roguish means for love.
你是说你和金面人
You mean you and Goldface.
男人
Men.
他们都是傻瓜  谁需要他们
They're all idiots. Who needs them?
这也许是一段美好友情的开始
This could be the start of a beautiful friendship!
跟我走
Come along.
我们这就去买花
We're going flower shopping.
金面人的帮派
Goldface's gang
正在向阿姆内特的一间仓库
is throwing Molotov cocktails
投掷燃烧瓶
at one of Amunet's warehouses.
他们在通过
They are retaliating
击沉他们最近的运输船来报复
by sinking their latest delivery boat.
我知道这是罪犯之间的事
I mean, I know it's criminal on criminal attacks right now,
但是如果我们不制止
but if we don't stop it, I mean,
这可能成为市民遇难的
it could be a Valentine's Day massacre
情人节大屠杀
where civilians get hurt.
我会继续巡逻城市
Yeah, no, I'll keep doing sweeps.
尽我所能帮助你
I'll help wherever I can.
我可能得组建一个超能力行动小组
Well, I might have to roll out a special meta taskforce.
你能召集闪电侠小队吗
Can you pull together Team Flash?
不  我不能  她都认识他们
No, I can't. I mean, she knows them all.
我也得保护他们的身份
I have to protect their identities too.
乔  关于阿姆内特和金面人
You know what, Joe, there's something not right
有些事情不太对
about this Amunet-Goldface thing, and...
爱瑞丝认为有个人问题牵涉其中
Iris thinks there's something personal going on.
我确实希望他们还是一对
Well, I mean, I do wish they were still a couple.
那时候外面的事情更安静安全些
I mean, things were a lot quieter out there and safer.
真是个不同的情人节啊
Some Valentine's Day, huh?
巴里
Barry.
你一直在低头看
You've been looking down a lot.
我这的地板可没那么好看  你怎么了
My floor's not that interesting, so what's up?
是爱瑞丝
It's Iris.
我是说她  我也不知道  只是突然之间
I mean, she--I don't know, it's just something
我们俩之间有些不对劲
that's suddenly off between us,
或者至少我觉得这事挺突然的
or at least it feels sudden to me.
那她是怎么说的
And what'd she say about that?
她已经成长了
She's grown,
但我还没有接受这一点
and I haven't accepted it.
我不太清楚第二句话该怎么办
Mm, I don't know about that second part,
但是第一句话
but that first part?
她确实成长了
She has grown.
她击败了一个黑洞的杀手
She took down a Black Hole assassin.
而且在危机之中
And she led the charge
她负责寻找到了蔡瑞安
to find Ryan Choi during Crisis.
而且她是唯一一个知道
And she was the only one
罗素并没有完全控制住你的人
who knew that Rosso hadn't completely taken you over.
这些对你来说意味着什么
I mean, what does that sound like to you?
我知道
I know.
我知道她已经成长了
I mean, she has grown,
我想她是对的
and I guess she was right.
我之前没有注意到
I mean, I didn't notice
因为我全身心都耗在处理危机上了
because I was consumed with Crisis.
可我们已经不像之前那样合拍了
We're just not clicking like usual though.
你觉得她是不是已经和我渐行渐远了
Do you think maybe she's grown apart?
巴里  不  不是的
Barry, no. No.
你们两个都不会停止成长的
Neither one of you are ever gonna stop growing.
其实婚姻就像是一棵树
I mean, marriage is like a tree.
耐心听我说
I mean, bear with me.
是这样  那些树枝
Look, the branches,
会从树干上伸展出去
they grow from the center.
它们会离树干越来越远
They grow farther and farther away from the center,
但你需要记住的是在泥土之下
but what you have to remember is underneath,
那些树根
the roots?
它们正是树枝的镜像
They're mirroring the branches.
树枝和树根生长得一样多
They're growing just as much.
所以你也是在巩固你的根基
So you're growing your foundation.
当然了  你必须好好照料好土地
Now of course, you gotta tend to the soil,
彼此之间不断交流沟通
communicate with each other,
照顾好彼此
take care of each other,
为彼此担惊受怕  但是...
look out for each other, but...
随着树枝的生长
as the branches grow,
你的根基也在生长
so does your foundation.
所以你们其实在一起成长
So you grow together.
艺术治疗  我也试过
Art therapy. Been there.
听我说  吉特咖啡店的事我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry about Jitters.
我知道你是好意
I know you meant well.
不  是我对不起
No, I'm sorry.
我的人生导师让我的生活变得更好了
Look, my life coach made my life better.
我只是想把这份爱传递出去
I was just trying to pay it forward.
我大概应该在尝试干预你之前
I probably should've gotten the whole story
忘掉所有
about your breakup
有关你分手的事
before trying to intervene.
我想我也没有完全敞开心怀
I guess I haven't exactly been an open book.
那就从头开始说吧
Why don't you start from page one?
我离开铁山监狱之后
After I got out of Iron Heights,
我想要试着过那种
I wanted to take a shot
没有超能力的正常生活
at living a normal, non-meta life.
也是在那个时候我碰到了爱默生
That's when I met Emerson.
我们成为了朋友
We became friends.
然后我们约了几次会
Then we went on a few dates.
一起大笑
Had some laughs.
但这段感情走到了尽头
But it ran its course,
所以我就放弃了
so I dropped it.
你不辞而别了
You ghosted him.
差不多吧
Kind of.
为什么
Why?
你不希望让他发现你是一个超能力者吧
You didn't want him to find out you're a meta.
过去我很难处理好我的超能力
Back then, I could barely deal with my powers.
我又怎么能期望别人能够做到呢
How could I expect someone else to?
反正我们本来就没有可能
Anyway, it was never gonna work between us.
你又不知道
You don't know that.
你也从未给过他机会
I mean, you never gave him a chance
让他了解真实的你
to find out who you really are.
现在无所谓了
It doesn't matter now.
估计他还恨着我不辞而别
He probably hates me for ghosting him.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
也许他一直在找你
'Cause maybe he's been looking for you every day since.
或者他不记得你还存在
Or maybe he forgot you existed.
不管怎样  你不知道是因为
Whatever it is, you don't know
你用胡思乱想
because you've been filling in the blanks
来猜测不知道的事
without the facts.
向埃默森坦白
Coming clean to Emerson
也许会让你感觉好很多
might actually make you feel a lot better.
谁知道呢
And who knows?
或许你们能成为朋友
Maybe you'll get a friend out of it.
但你不能认为生活是
But you can't assume that life happens
非黑即白的
in black and white,
因为生活是灰色的
because life happens in the gray,
你要走出去  自己面对生活
and you need to get out there and live in it.
基思和我在一起时
Keith and I were like fireworks
就像烟花
when we were together.
我们的志向相同  这也点燃了我们
We shared the same ambitions, and it ignited us both.
我们激励彼此
We inspired each other.
伯西尼之女本该是我们的最大一票
Rappaccini's Daughter was meant to be our greatest score ever.
既是它每二十五年才开一次花吗
Even though it only blooms every 25 years?
怎么说呢
What can I say?
我们乐观主义者总是为将来做打算
We were optimists, making plans for the future.
我们知道它今年准备开花
We knew that it was set to bloom this year,
等我们得到它的读心能力
and once we had our hands on its mindreading powers,
我们就无人可挡了
no one would be able to stop us.
我们会一同掌控这座城市
We would run this town together.
只有在和他在一起时我才能做我自己
I felt like I could be myself when I was with him.
只有他能看到我的内在
He's the only one who ever saw beyond all this.
看到真正的我
He saw me for me.
哪里出差错了
So what went wrong?
我们的关系并没有和生意一样变好
Hmm, as business boomed, our relationship didn't.
我们的激情逐渐
Our passion wilted
消逝殆尽
and died.
阿姆内特  我不知道
I don't know, Amunet.
你们两个都想杀死对方
The way you two were trying to kill each other--
爱与恨之间只隔一道线  亲爱的
It's a fine line between love and hate, my dear.
谢谢
Thank you.
你为什么不告诉他你的感受
Why don't you just tell him how you feel?
和他谈谈
Talk to him.
不行
No.
没有他我过的更好
I'm better off without him.
等我拿到那朵花
And when I get my hands on that flower,
我要自己掌控这座城市
I'll run this town myself.
来吧  小的们
Come, my lovelies.
你好  亲爱的
Hello, lover.
那个箱子
That case.
看起来像是你偷走科技的增大版
It looks like a larger version of the tech that you stole.
这种兰花
This orchid
很像爱情
is a lot like love.
只能在
It can only survive
悉心照料的环境下生存
in a carefully tended environment.
你给我的玻璃仪器
That glass device you gave me
是一个微型生物群落模拟器
is a miniature biome simulator.
紫外线投影仪提供光照
The UV projector provides a nurturing light.
结合在一起
Together,
就是爱情
l'amour.
这花
Flowers.
不是你的
You shouldn't have.
既然你已经有了运送花朵的方法
Seeing that you got the means to transport the flower,
我就一起从你手上抢走
I figured I'd take them both from you once.
就当是情人节礼物
Consider it a Valentine's gift.
我还以为今年不互送礼物了
And here I thought we weren't exchanging gifts this year.
情人节快乐
Happy Valentine's Day.
巴里  你在干什么
Barry, what are you doing?
阿姆内特不能看到闪电侠
Amunet can't see the Flash here.
我不想再和她玩下去了
I'm done playing her game,
无论如何我都要来救你
and I'll risk anything to save you.
把你挖出的线索拼凑起来之后
Look, after piecing together the leads that you dug up,
不难发现
it wasn't hard to figure out
他们在追踪拉伯西尼之女
that they were after Rappaccini's Daughter.
他们是要拼个你死我活
They're gonna destroy each other.
除非他们两个都承认
Not if they both accept that they still
自己对对方余情未了
have feelings for each other.
乔确实说过他们没分手的时候比较好说话
Joe did say things were better when they were together.
和你分手后我过得更好了
My life got better without you.
你就是个拖后腿的
You're dead weight.
你是我犯过最大的错
You were the biggest mistake I ever made!
你总是有这么个该死的毛病
You always had this one really bad habit.
呼吸
Breathing!
你不过就是个廉价的光头版T先生
You are nothing but a cheap, bald Mr. T.
我要阻止他们交火
I'm gonna stop their crossfire.
我宁愿和诺福克约会也不要理你
I'd rather date Norvock than you.
我也这么想
That makes two of us!
你的美国口音烂爆了
Your American accent sucks!
你的口音也烂爆了
So does yours!
我在康涅狄格长大的  我上过耶鲁
I'm from Connecticut. I went to Yale.
好了  住手  别打了
Okay, stop. Just stop this.
你们曾经在一起很快乐  对吗
You guys were happy together once, right?
你们为什么分手
Why'd you break up?
我想我说过了
I thought I said--
她不再听我说话了
She stopped listening to me.
碰到糟心事后  我需要的是她的支持
I needed her support when things went bad,
而不是冷眼相待
not her cold shoulder.
我厌倦了他总是和兄弟们庆祝成功
I got tired of him always celebrating with his posse
但在我面前只会抱怨自己的失败
and only coming to me to whine about his failures.
-很让人厌烦  -看到了吗
- It got old! - Okay, see?
我是说  你们现在开始交流了
I mean, you guys are talking now.
这样很好  对吧
This is great, right?
我说了别穿连体衣了
I said no onesie.
行吧  为什么所有人总这么叫它
Okay, why does everybody keep calling it that?
不管你叫它什么
Whatever you call it,
它里面可含有不少金  闪电侠
there's an awful lot of gold in there, Flash.
老天
Oh, God.
好了  我们说到哪里了
Now, where were we?
我刚想告诉你
I was just about to tell you
我说我喜欢你的狗的时候
when I told you I liked your dog,
我撒谎了  我喜欢猫
I lied! I'm a cat person.
你晚上敷的泥浆面膜闻起来臭死了
The mud mask you use at night smells rank.
地里的土都比那个好闻
Real mud smells better.
这滋味可不好受
Oh, that didn't feel great.
好吧  这招没用  他们没戏了
Okay, it's no use. There's no fixing them.
我有个主意
I have an idea,
但可能有点冒险
but it might be reckless.
计划是什么
What's the plan?
烧了那盆花
Burn the flower.
你又开始了  不停转你那根金闪闪的意面
There you go again, twirling your shiny spaghetti.
我想永远抱着你
I'd hold you forever,
但那依然让人觉得短暂
but it still wouldn't be enough time together.
你的眼神像金子一样填满了我的心
The sight of your eyes fills my heart with gold.
成了吗
Did it work?
夜空中的星辰只能幻想
The stars at night can only dream
有朝一日如你一般闪耀
they'd ever shine as bright as you.
我一直以你在耶鲁的成就为傲
I was always so proud of the work you did at Yale.
你的全天然泥浆面膜太神奇了
Your natural mud mask works wonders.
你让我变得完整
You complete me.
发生什么了
What's happening?
我想你了
I missed you.
我也想你
I missed you too.
对不起  我应该把手套脱掉的
Oh, I'm sorry. I should take off my gauntlet.
戴着吧  妹子
Leave it on, girl.
爸爸就喜欢金属
Daddy likes the metal.
这我没法视而不见
I can't unsee this.
至少没有聚众枪战暴力吧
Well, at least it's less violent than a gang war?
-彼此彼此  -是啊
- Barely. - Yeah.
比我记得的划痕还多
More nicks than I remember.
情人节快乐
Happy Valentine's Day.
结果怎么样
How'd it go?
比我想的要好
Better than I thought.
我为不辞而别向他道了歉
I said sorry for ghosting him.
告诉了他原因
Told him why.
他接受了我的道歉
He accepted my apology.
那他可以接受你有超能力
So he's fine with you being a meta?
原来他的新鼓手可以发荧光
Turns out his new drummer is bioluminescent.
爱默生和我又会成朋友了
Emerson and I are gonna be friends again.
告诉你
And you know what?
我觉得那才是一直以来我所怀念的
I think that's what I was really missing this whole time.
他也是  他还让我
Him too, he actually wants me to go
在他上台表演之前看一眼他的新歌词呢
take a look at his new lyrics before he goes on stage.
看看你  又重新成为他的灵感了
Look at you. Back to being a muse.
谢谢你
So, thanks
那些灰色生活什么的教导
for your help with all the gray life stuff.
正好是我需要听的
It's exactly what I needed to hear.
不要客气
You're welcome.
不过并不都是我的功劳
Although I can't take all the credit.
我的一位朋友给了我一些建议
A friend of mine did give me some advice.
那也谢谢他们吧
Well, tell them thanks too.
他们也许不认识我  但却理解我
They may not know me, but they get me.
冰霜  我是叫...
Frost. I mean...
你
you.
收到你的信息了  什么事这么重要
Got your message. What's so important?
我觉得你可能想知道阿莱格拉在这
I thought you'd want to know that Allegra was here
这样你就可以把那工具玩意给她
so you could give her your tool thingy.
你开玩笑呢吧  真的吗
The--are you kidding? Really?
你叫我来个不怎么样的
You bring me to a crappy
情人节观众上台之夜就为这个
Valentine's Day open mic night for that?
还有这样我可以告诉你我欠你个人情
Well, also so I could tell you that I owe you one.
你给我的建议  帮助我
The advice you gave, it really helped me
说服了阿莱格拉
get through to Allegra.
说得很有见地
It was very insightful.
几乎像是家长说的
Almost parental.
你说这话有什么意图吗
You going somewhere with that?
我的意思是  以后如果你想找人聊聊
I'm just saying, if you ever want to talk,
就像我说的  我欠你的情
like I said, I owe you one.
而且我非常善于聆听
And I'm a very good listener.
这情人节过的
Hell of a Valentine's Day, huh?
明年我们把我们关到时间穹顶里
Next year, we lock ourselves in the Time Vault
早上再出来
and don't come out till morning.
听着
Listen,
很抱歉我让你感觉
I'm really sorry that I made you feel
我没从更大的意义上看到你的成功
like I wasn't seeing all your success in a larger way.
-宝贝  没什么  -不对
- Babe, it's fine. - No, it's not.
你为自己闯出了名气
You've made a name for yourself,
整座城市都依靠你和《公民报》
and this city looks to you and the "Citizen"
来获取真相
for the truth about what's going on.
而我对于你
And I am so proud of who you are
和你所取得的所有成感到骄傲
and all of your accomplishments.
我只是...
I just...
今天有那么一刻  我感觉...
...for a moment today,  I felt like...
也许我们要分开了
Maybe we're going apart.
那永远也不可能
That will never happen.
我现在知道了
I get that.
宝贝记住  无论发生什么变故
And babe then just remember that no matter what changes
你也将永远是我的避雷针
you are always going be my lightning rod, too.
爱瑞丝·韦斯特艾伦
Iris West-Allen,
做我的情人节情人好吗
will you be my Valentine?
你知道我在想什么
You read my mind.
离他远点
Get away from him!
巴里
Barry!
那不是我
It's not me!
她不是我
She's not me!
巴里
Barry!